<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>viz on Johanie Fournier</title>
    <link>https://johaniefournier.com/tag/viz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in viz on Johanie Fournier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johaniefournier.com/tag/viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Trends to Predictions: Machine Learning Forecasts for Centre-du-Québec’s Precipitation</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cdq_precipitation_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cdq_precipitation_ml/</guid>
      <description>In this phase of the analysis, we aim to model precipitation patterns in Centre-du-Québec using machine learning techniques, leveraging historical climate and environmental data. We will train an XGBoost models and predict precipitation trends. Model performance will be evaluated using cross-validation and regression metrics to determine the most effective approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Years of Precipitation for Centre-du-Québec: Trends, Patterns &amp; Anomalies</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cdq_precipitation_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cdq_precipitation_eda/</guid>
      <description>Understanding long-term precipitation patterns is crucial for climate research, agriculture, and water resource management. In this post, we analyze 30 years of high-resolution precipitation data from the AgERA5 dataset, focusing on a single administrative region in Quebec. Using exploratory data analysis (EDA) techniques, we uncover trends, seasonal variations, and anomalies to gain deeper insights into precipitation dynamics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Lawrence Lowlands Precipitation Data: 30-Year Trends Prediction</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/st_lawrence_lowlands_precipitation_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/st_lawrence_lowlands_precipitation_ml/</guid>
      <description>In this phase of the analysis, we aim to model precipitation patterns in the St. Lawrence Lowlands using machine learning techniques, leveraging historical climate and environmental data. We will compare Random Forest, XGBoost, and Mars models to assess their ability to capture complex relationships and predict precipitation trends. Model performance will be evaluated using cross-validation and regression metrics to determine the most effective approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Lawrence Lowlands Precipitation Data: 30-Year Trends &amp; Anomalies</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/st_lawrence_lowlands_precipitation_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/st_lawrence_lowlands_precipitation_eda/</guid>
      <description>Understanding long-term precipitation patterns is essential for climate research, agriculture, and water resource management. In this post, we analyze 30 years of precipitation data from the AgERA5 dataset for St. Lawrence Lowlands, using exploratory data analysis (EDA) techniques to uncover trends, seasonal variations, and anomalies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TyT2024W21 - VIZ:Carbon Majors Emissions Data</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/tyt2024w21_viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/tyt2024w21_viz/</guid>
      <description>This week we are exploring historical emissions data from Carbon Majors. They have complied a database of emissions data going back to 1854. In the first and second part I did some EDA and created a spatio-temporal machine learning model. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m creating an animated vizualisation of the data including the prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is the begining of a cheat sheet!</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I will list here all the little snipset of code that I look up all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
