<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ressources on Johanie Fournier</title>
    <link>https://johaniefournier.com/tag/ressources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ressources on Johanie Fournier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johaniefournier.com/tag/ressources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Valorisation in Agriculture? 10 Ways to Turn Raw Data into Real Value</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/valorisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/valorisation/</guid>
      <description>Want to make better use of your farm data? In this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover what data valorisation means in agriculture and how to apply it using real-world examples, practical tools, and a mindset shift. From soil tests to weather records, learn how to turn everyday data into smarter decisions and better outcomes—without needing complex technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Resources to Learn, Grow, and Work Smarter</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/ressources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/ressources/</guid>
      <description>Here are the resources for data analysts and programmers I personally recommend — including the best R programming books, top data science courses, and productivity tools for developers that I use to stay organized and learn faster. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re starting out or growing your career, these tools and learning paths can help you learn R programming faster and build real-world skills. (Some links are affiliate links. They cost you nothing extra and help support my work. Thanks!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 Online Courses to Level Up Your R Programming and Data Science Skills (2025 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/courses/</guid>
      <description>Discover the best R programming and data science courses to boost your skills, build real-world projects, and grow your career. Start learning smarter today!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
