<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>eda on Johanie Fournier</title>
    <link>https://johaniefournier.com/tag/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in eda on Johanie Fournier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johaniefournier.com/tag/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Temperature and GDD Trends Are Transforming the Growing Season in Chaudières-Appalaches?</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/ca_temperature_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/ca_temperature_eda/</guid>
      <description>How is climate change affecting temperature, Growing Degree Days (GDD), and the vegetation period in Chaudières-Appalaches? This analysis explores 20 years of historical climate data, uncovering trends, anomalies, and shifts in temperature patterns. By examining GDD calculations and vegetation period variations, we highlight the impacts on agriculture, crop cycles, and ecosystem resilience. Using R for data analysis and visualization, this study provides key insights into how climate trends are reshaping growing conditions in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Years of Precipitation for Centre-du-Québec: Trends, Patterns &amp; Anomalies</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cdq_precipitation_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cdq_precipitation_eda/</guid>
      <description>Understanding long-term precipitation patterns is crucial for climate research, agriculture, and water resource management. In this post, we analyze 30 years of high-resolution precipitation data from the AgERA5 dataset, focusing on a single administrative region in Quebec. Using exploratory data analysis (EDA) techniques, we uncover trends, seasonal variations, and anomalies to gain deeper insights into precipitation dynamics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Lawrence Lowlands Precipitation Data: 30-Year Trends &amp; Anomalies</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/st_lawrence_lowlands_precipitation_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/st_lawrence_lowlands_precipitation_eda/</guid>
      <description>Understanding long-term precipitation patterns is essential for climate research, agriculture, and water resource management. In this post, we analyze 30 years of precipitation data from the AgERA5 dataset for St. Lawrence Lowlands, using exploratory data analysis (EDA) techniques to uncover trends, seasonal variations, and anomalies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TyT2024W21 - EDA:Carbon Majors Emissions Data</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/tyt2024w21_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/tyt2024w21_eda/</guid>
      <description>This week we are exploring historical emissions data from Carbon Majors. They have complied a database of emissions data going back to 1854. In this first part, I start with some exploratory data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is the begining of a cheat sheet!</title>
      <link>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johaniefournier.com/blog/cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I will list here all the little snipset of code that I look up all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
